Samantha Dickeson (she / her)

FULL-STACK SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

A senior software engineer at NearSt, with 6+ years experience coding in JavaScript & TypeScript. I like making things, solving problems and making things that solve problems.

I'm also a Psychology graduate, and before learning web development I worked in data analysis for four years, before teaching myself to code and joining the Founders & Coders bootcamp.

I'm looking for roles based in London, with 2+ days remote per week.

EXPERIENCE

NearSt — Senior Software Engineer

AUGUST 2019 - PRESENT | SENIOR FROM IULY 2022

Working at a smaller start-up has given me the freedom to grow, learn, and take on big challenges, all the way up to senior level.

On a day to day basis, I pair, mob or work independently, using coding best practices to write well-tested, maintainable code. We use continuous deployment, and all of our code is tested and deployed to AWS via our CI/CD pipeline in GitHub Actions.

Throughout my time at NearSt, I've been lucky enough to work on a huge range of projects, from frontend component design to database migrations. Here are some of my favourite challenges:

- Designing, architecting and maintaining our core pipeline, a distributed, event-driven, serverless microservice architecture at scale - processing over 1B records daily with AWS S3, Kinesis, Lambda and DynamoDB
- Leading several refactors and improvements to our React frontend, with a particular focus on DX and loading speed and including a migration of our OAuth provider
- Over the years, I've taken ownership of the growth of our insights pipeline - from an experimental data lake using S3, Glue and Athena, to an Aurora-based Postgres database using SQL, handling over 250GB of data
- More recently, some fascinating entirely serverless, event-driven architecture to handle web scraping at scale (millions of concurrent requests)

Founders and Coders - Bootcamp

MARCH 2019 - JULY 2019

At Founders and Coders I learned full-stack web development, including testing, Node, PostgresQL, Express and React.

The course had a focus on cooperation and pair programming. I also gained hands-on design and agile build sprint experience working on real-world projects.



github.com/starsuit



samlucydickeson@gmail.com



in linkedin.com/in/sdickeson

STACK / SKILLS

- Node
- React
- Jest & Cypress (S)CSS
- SQL
- Next
- Python
- AI tooling
- TDD
- CI/CD

SERVERLESS & AWS:

- S3
- Aurora RDS
- Lambda
- Glue & ETL
- DynamoDB
- Athena
- Kinesis

- CDK
- Step Functions SQS & SNS

PRE-DEV EXPERIENCE

Vanguard Learning Trust, Ickenham — Data Manager

DECEMBER 2015 - MARCH 2019

Xerox UK, Uxbridge — Data Migration Analyst

MARCH 2015 - DECEMBER 2015

EDUCATION

Reading University — BSc Psychology 2:1

OCTOBER 2010 - JUNE 2014